A Guide to the Davis General Store Records, 1957-1972
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Davis General Store Records, 1957-1972
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 02-03
12.5 linear feet
The Davis General Store Records consists of 12.5 linear feet and spans the years 1957-1972 and includes the record books and daily receipts of expenditures at the Fairfax Station, Virginia store.
Davis, Shirley Dove (1931-2014)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Shirley Davis’ daughters, Linda Davis and Andrea Shimer on July 1, 2015.
Historical and Biographical Information
What today is known as the Davis General Store at 7600 Clifton Road traces its roots back to Isaac Frank Woodyard. Woodyard bought the land at the intersection of Wolf Run Shoals Road and Clifton Road in March 1883. Shortly thereafter he opened a two-story frame general store on the site known as Woodyard’s Store. On June 5, 1907, George C. Fairfax shot and killed Woodyard in his store over a dispute over the location of the local polling place. After the authorities arrested him, Fairfax committed suicide.
Woodyard’s widow rented the store out to brothers Robert and Eugene Makely and eventually sold it to them on December 2, 1911. They renamed it Makely’s Store and also added a gasoline pump. The corner is still known as Makely’s Corner to this day. The Makely family sold the store in 1938 and it changed hands several times. In January 1955, Herbert A. Urie bought the store and renamed it Urie’s Community Market. Leighton and Shirley Davis bought it from Urie on August 5, 1957 and it has been known as the Davis General Store ever since. The couple had worked at the store for some years prior and in 1951, they built a house across the street from it.
By 1964 the business had outgrown the old frame building. Practically located in the middle of the intersection due to the crossroads expansion over the years, the Davises decided to construct a newer building further away from the road. They opened the current flat-roofed cinderblock store on April 3, 1965, and had the original building razed.
In 1973, the Davises leased out the store and eventually sold it in 1985. The store’s ownership has changed numerous times since and the building itself has been modernized over the years. Leighton Davis died on December 5, 1990 and Shirley Davis passed away on February 27, 2014.
Scope and Content
The Davis General Store Records consists of 12.5 linear feet and spans the years 1957-1972 and includes the record books and daily receipts of expenditures at the Fairfax Station, Virginia store. These records, maintained by co-owner Shirley Dove Davis, include complete daily receipts of products she purchased to sell in the store ranging from local newspapers to bakery goods to candy bars and automobile parts. She purchased goods from local businesses and farmers as well as national distributers. The receipts are kept in their original order. Subjects include Fairfax Station and Clifton, Virginia as well as the history of general store operations, material culture and products bought in Fairfax County during the 1950s-1970s.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Clifton (Va.); Davis, Shirley Dove (1931-2014); Davis, Leighton E. (1925-1990); Davis General Store; Fairfax Station (Va.); General stores - Virginia - Fairfax County - History; Material culture - Virginia - Fairfax County - History; Small business - Virginia - Fairfax County - History
Container List
- Receipts, 1957 August (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1957 September (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1957 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1957 November (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1957 December (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1958 January (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1958 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1958 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1958 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1958 May (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1958 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1958 July (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1958 August (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1958 September (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1958 October (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1958 November (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1958 December (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1959 January (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1959 February (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1959 March (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1959 April (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1959 May (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1959 June (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1959 July (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1959 August (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1959 September (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1959 October (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1959 November (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1959 December (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1960 January (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1960 February (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1960 March (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1960 April (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1960 May (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1960 June (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1960 July (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1960 August (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1960 September (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1960 October (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1960 November (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1960 December (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1961 January (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1961 February (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1961 March (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1961 April (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1961 May (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1961 June (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1961 July (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1961 August (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1961 September (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1961 October (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1961 November (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1961 December (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1962 January (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1962 February (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1962 March (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1962 April (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1962 May (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1962 June (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1962 July (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1962 August (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1962 September (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1962 October (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1962 November (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1962 December (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1963 January (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1963 February (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1963 March (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1963 April (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1963 May (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1963 June (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1963 July (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1963 August (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1963 September (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1963 October (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1963 November (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1963 December (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1964 January (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1964 February (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1964 March (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1964 April (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1964 May (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1964 June (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1964 July (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1964 August (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1964 September (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1964 October (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1964 November (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1964 December (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1965 January (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1965 February (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1965 March 1-13 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1965 March 14-31 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1965 April 1-18 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1965 April 19-30 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1965 May 1-16 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1965 May 17-31 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1965 June 1-13 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1965 June 14-30 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1965 July 1-11 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1965 July 12-31 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1965 August 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1965 August 16-31 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1965 September 1-12 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1965 September 13-19 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1965 September 20-30 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1965 October 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1965 October 11-17 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1965 October 18-31 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1965 November 1-14 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Receipts, 1965 November 15-30 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Receipts, 1965 December 1-12 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Receipts, 1965 December 13-31 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Receipts, 1966 January 1-16 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Receipts, 1966 January 17-31 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Receipts, 1966 February 1-13 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Receipts, 1966 February 14-28 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Receipts, 1966 March 1-13 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Receipts, 1966 March 14-31 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Receipts, 1966 April 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Receipts, 1966 April 11-30 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1966 May 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1966 May 16-31 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1966 June 1-12 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1966 June 13-30 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1966 July 1-17 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1966 July 18-31 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1966 August 1-14 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1966 August 15-31 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1966 September 1-11 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1966 September 12-30 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1966 October 1-16 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1966 October 17-31 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1966 November 1-13 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1966 November 14-30 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1966 December 1-11 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1966 December 12-31 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1967 January 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1967 January 16-31 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1967 February 1-12 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1967 February 13-28 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1967 March 1-12 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1967 March 13-31 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1967 April 1-16 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Receipts, 1967 April 17-30 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Receipts, 1967 May 1-14 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Receipts, 1967 May 15-31 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1967 June 1-18 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1967 June 19-30 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1967 July 1-16 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1967 July 17-31 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1967 August 1-13 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1967 August 14-31 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1968 January 1-14 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1968 January 15-31 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1968 February 1-18 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1968 February 19-29 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1968 March 1-17 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1968 March 18-31 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1968 April 1-14 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1968 April 15-30 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1968 May 1-12 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1968 May 13-31 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1968 June 1-16 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1968 June 18-30 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1968 July 1-14 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1968 July 15-31 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1968 August 1-18 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1968 August 19-31 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1968 September 1-15 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1968 September 16-30 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1968 October 1-14 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1968 October 15-31 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1968 November 1-17 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1968 November 18-30 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1968 December 1-15 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1968 December 16-31 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1969 January 1-12 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1969 January 13-31 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1969 February 1-16 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1969 February 17-28 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1969 March 1-16 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1969 March 17-31 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1969 April 1-13 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1969 April 14-30 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1969 May 1-14 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1969 May 15-31 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1969 June 1-15 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1969 June 16-30 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Receipts, 1969 July 1-13 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Receipts, 1969 July 14-31 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Receipts, 1969 August 1-17 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Receipts, 1969 August 18-31 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Receipts, 1969 September 1-14 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Receipts, 1969 September 15-30 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Receipts, 1969 October 1-19 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1969 October 20-31 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1969 November 1-16 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1969 November 17-30 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1969 December 1-14 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1969 December 15-31 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1970 January 1-18 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1970 January 19-31 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1970 February 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1970 February 16-28 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1970 March 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1970 March 16-31 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1970 April 1-12 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1970 April 13-30 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1970 May 1-17 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1970 May 18-31 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1970 June 1-14 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1970 June 15-30 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1970 July 1-12 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1970 July 13-31 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1970 August 1-16 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1970 August 17-31 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1970 September 1-13 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1970 September 14-30 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Receipts, 1970 October 1-18 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Receipts, 1970 October 19-31 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Receipts, 1970 November 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Receipts, 1970 December 1-13 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Receipts, 1970 December 14-31 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Receipts, 1971 January 1-17 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1971 January 18-31 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1971 February 1-14 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1971 February 15-28 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1971 March 1-14 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1971 March 15-31 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1971 April 1-18 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1971 April 19-30 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1971 May 1-16 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1971 May 17-31 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1971 June 1-13 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1971 June 14-30 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1971 July 1-18 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1971 July 19-31 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1971 August 1-15 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1971 August 16-31 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1971 September 1-12 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1971 September 13-30 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1971 October 1-17 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1971 October 18- 31 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1971 November 1-14 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1971 November 15-30 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1971 December 1-12 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1971 December 13-31 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Receipts, 1972 January 1-16 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1972 January 17-31 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1972 February 1-13 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1972 February 14-29 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1972 March 1-12 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1972 March 13-31 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1972 April 1-16 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1972 April 17-30 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1972 May 1-14 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1972 May 15-31 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1972 June 1-18 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1972 June 19-30 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Receipts, 1972 July 1-16 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Receipts, 1972 July 17-31 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Receipts, 1972 August 1-13 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Receipts, 1972 August 14-31 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Receipts, 1972 September 1-17 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Receipts, 1972 September 18-31 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1972 October 1-15 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1972 October 16-31 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1972 November 1-12 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1972 November 13-30 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1972 December 1-17 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1972 December 18-31 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Record Book, 1957 August 5 - 1958 November 7 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Record Book, 1958 November 8 - 1960 March 6 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Record Book, 1960 March 7 - 1961 July 2 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Record Book, 1961 July 3 - 1962 December 31 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Record Book, 1963 January 1 - 1963 November 17 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Record Book, 1963 November 18 - 1964 December 31 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Record Book, 1965 January 1 - November 14 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Record Book, 1965 November 15 - 1966 September 25 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Record Book, 1966 September 26 - 1967 July 23 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Record Book, 1967 July 24 - 1968 June 9 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Record Book, 1968 June 10 - 1969 December 31 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Record Book, 1970 January 1 - November 15 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Record Book, 1970 November 16 - 1971 September 26 (Box 12, Folder 13)